Guide to the Few Family Papers, 1861-2009 (bulk 1905-1967) UA.03.55.0002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Few Family papers
1861-2009 (bulk 1905-1967)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Few family
UA.03.55.0002
27 Linear Feet
The Few family papers includes correspondence, business and financial papers, clippings, printed material, and genealogical information. The collection was created by various members of the Thomas and Few families, with the majority being created by Mary Reamey Thomas Few and her husband, Dr. William P. Few, president of Trinity College (1910-1924) and Duke University (1924-1940). The collection ranges in date from 1861-1986 (bulk 1905-1967).
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
Provenance
The majority of the political papers portion of the Few Family Papers was received as a purchase in 1978. The rest was received by the University Archives in 1972, between 1990-1991, and in 2016.
Biographical Note
Mary Reamey Thomas Few was born on July 12, 1885 in Martinsville, Va. to Lyne Starling and Elizabeth Sheffield Thomas. Educated by private tutors throughout her childhood, she entered Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) in 1902 and graduated magna cum laude in 1906. While at Trinity College, Mrs. Few as a member of the first staff of The Chronicle and also served on the staff of The Archive. Additionally, Mrs. Few was a member of the Kappa Delta sorority. In 1907, she earned a M.A. in English from Columbia University. She taught at the Southern Seminary in Buena Vista, Va. until the end of the 1910 session. On August 17, 1911, she married Dr. William Preston Few.
Born in Greenville, S.C. on December 29, 1867, the son of Benjamin Franklin and Rachel Kendrick Few, William Preston Few attended Wofford College, Spartanburg S.C. (A.B., 1889), and Harvard University (A.M., 1893; Ph.D., 1896). Dr. Few came to Durham in 1896 as Professor of English at Trinity College. He was named Dean of the College in 1902, and President in 1910, succeeding John C. Kilgo. Dr. Few was President of Trinity College/Duke University from 1910-1940.
President and Mrs. Few had five sons: William Few (1/4/1912-12/9/1979), Lyne Starling Few (10/18/1913-12/19/2004), Kendrick Sheffield Few (8/1/1917-7/27/1996), Randolph Reamey Few (10/6/1920-10/14/2008), and Yancy Preston Few (1922-1939). Dr. Few died on October 16, 1940.
After the death of her husband, Mrs. Few became active in the affairs of the Republican Party. She served as Republican national committeewoman for North Carolina from 1944-1956 and as a member of the Republican National Executive Committee. She was a member of the Platform Committee and the Commmittee on Arrangements for the Republican National Convention in 1948 as a delegate-at-large and Platform Committee for the Convention in 1952, where she supported Dwight D. Eisenhower for the presidential nomination. Mrs. Few died on January 8, 1971.
Collection Overview
The Few family papers encompass two families: the Few family and the Thomas family. The majority of the collection was created by Mary Reamey Thomas Few and her husband, Dr. William P. Few. The collection is divided into six series: Correspondence, Genealogy, Miscellaneous, Political Papers of Mary Reamey Thomas Few, Family Materials, and Duke University Materials.
The Correspondence series is broken down into several subseries based on how the correspondence was grouped by the Few family. The majority of the correspondence was written by and to members of the Few and Thomas families, including letters between Dr. and Mrs. Few prior to their marriage as well as letters from Mrs. Few to her parents while she was an undergraduate at Trinity College (Durham, N.C.). Other subjects in the correspondence series include family and business matters and social conditions in Durham, as well as letters and telegrams sent to the family after the death of William Preston Few in 1940.
The Genealogy series includes research notes and information accumulated by Mrs. Few as well as applications for membership in several historical and genealogical societies.
The Miscelleanous series includes financial and business papers, Lyne Starling Thomas' business papers, printed material, clippings, and address/memo books.
The Political Papers series consists of correspondence, memorabilia, pamphlets, clippings, photographs and printed materials amassed by Mary Reamey Thomas Few in her capacity as a leader in the Republican Party.
The Family Materials subseries contains photographs, memorabilia, business papers, clippings, certificates and diplomas, and other materials collected by William Preston Few, Mary Randolph Few, and their sons.
The Duke University Materials series contains photographs, magazines, newspaper clippings, correspondence, booklets and brochures, and other items relating to the history of Duke University and Trinity College, collected by members of the Few family, primarily Mary Reamey Thomas Few.
Many files contain handwritten notes identifying the contents, written by the family members who originally organized and identified the materials.
Presidents -- United States -- Election; Elections -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Campaign literature -- North Carolina; Campaign literature -- History -- 20th century; Durham (N.C.) -- Social conditions; North Carolina -- Politics and government; Durham (N.C.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century; Martinsville (Va.); Few, W. P. (William Preston), 1867-1940; Few, Mary Reamey Thomas; Few family; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- Students -- Social life and customs; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- Students, societies, etc.; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- Students; Women's Republican Club of America; Republican National Committee (U.S.); Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ) -- History -- 20th century; Thomas family; Thomas, Elizabeth Sheffield; Thomas, Lyne Starling; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- Alumni and alumnae; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- Faculty; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- History -- 20th century
- Correspondence, 1861-1994
  Scope and Contents note
  The family correspondence in the original accession was sorted and grouped by Kendrick and/or Randolph Few, sons of Dr. William and Mary Few. Correspondence from accession UA2016.0033 was preliminarily sorted by Dana Few Pope, daughter of Randolph Few. At processing, the letters were sorted by date within each grouping for easier patron access and use. Each grouping is a sub-series named for the creator of the correspondence, if applicable.
  Mary Few's correspondence varies in content, depending on the recipient. The letters to her parents detail her life as an undergraduate at Trinity College in Durham, with references to her classes, professors, friends and social activities. She writes of her visits to Benjamin Duke's house to visit his daughter Mary and going "automobiling." Some of her social activities included traveling throughout North Carolina with college friends, joining her classmates for dinner at the home of James Southgate (Trinity College trustee), and attending religious meetings and theatrical productions. Of note are Mrs. Few's letters home regarding the 1905 visit of President Theodore "Teddy" Roosevelt to Trinity College. Mrs. Few's letters continue through her time at Columbia University, Southern Seminary in Buena Vista, Va., and finally her return to Durham after her marriage to Dr. Few. The later letters focus largely on family matters, including her sons and Dr. Few's travels.
  The letters exchanged between Dr. and Mrs. Few provide some insight into their long-distance courtship but largely focus on family matters. The remaining family-related correspondence also pertains to family matters but also business matters as well. The general correspondence subseries contains letters written mainly to Mrs. Few from various individuals about a wide array of topics, including business ventures and genealogy. One file contains letters to the Fews following the death of their son Yancy Preston Few in 1939.
  The Correspondence series also includes letters between Mrs. Few and her son Kendrick Few during the 1920s-1950s; as well as letters and telegrams sent to the family after the death of Dr. William Preston Few in 1940.
  - Correspondence written by Mary Reamey Thomas Few
    - To Elizabeth Sheffield Thomas [mother]
      - 1904-1905 Feb. (Box 1)
      - 1905 March-April (Box 1)
      - 1905 May-June (Box 1)
      - 1905 Oct. (Box 1)
      - 1905 Nov. (Box 1)
      - 1905 Dec. (Box 1)
      - 1906 Jan. (Box 1)
      - 1906 Feb. (Box 1)
      - 1906 Nov.-Dec. (Box 1)
      - 1907 Jan.-March (Box 1)
      - 1907 May-June (Box 2)
      - 1909 Jan.-March (Box 2)
      - 1909 April-June (Box 2)
      - 1912 (Box 2)
      - 1913 Jan.-Feb. (Box 2)
      - 1913 March-June (Box 2)
      - 1913 July-Aug. (Box 2)
      - 1913 Sept.-Oct. (Box 2)
      - 1913 Nov.-Dec., undetermined months for 1913 (Box 2)
      - 1914 Jan.-Feb. (Box 3)
      - 1914 Mar.-Apr. (Box 3)
      - 1914 May-June, Oct. (Box 3)
      - 1914 Nov.-Dec. (Box 3)
      - 1915 (Box 3)
      - 1916 (Box 3)
      - 1917 Feb.-May (Box 3)
      - 1917 July-Dec. (Box 3)
      - 1918 Jan.-Apr. (Box 3)
      - 1918 May-Dec. (Box 4)
      - 1919 Jan.-July (Box 4)
      - 1919 Sept.-Dec. (Box 4)
      - 1920, 1912, 1927 (Box 4)
    - To Lyne Starling Thomas [father]
      - 1904 Nov.-1905 (Box 4)
      - 1906-1907, 1909 (Box 4)
      - 1912-1918 (Box 4)
    - To William Preston Few [husband]
      - 1908-1911 (Box 4)
      - 1912-1913 (Box 4)
      - 1914 March-Nov. (Box 5)
      - 1915 (Box 5)
      - 1916 June-Aug. (Box 5)
      - 1916 Sept. (Box 5)
      - 1916 Oct.-1918 May (Box 5)
      - 1918 June-Nov. (Box 5)
      - 1919 March, July-Aug. (Box 5)
      - 1919 Sept.-Nov. (Box 6)
      - 1920 (Box 6)
      - 1922-1927 (Box 6)
      - 1933 Dec.-1934 (Box 6)
      - 1935-1937 (Box 6)
      - 1938 (Box 6)
      - 1939-1940 (Box 6)
      - Undated (Box 6)
    - To Kendrick Sheffield Few [son]
      - 1924-1957, undated (Box 28)
        Scope and Contents
        Includes letters written by William Preston Few and other correspondents.
      - 1942, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 28)
      - 1943-1944 (Box 28)
      - circa 1944-1946 (Box 28)
      - 1945 (Box 28)
      - 1946 (Box 28)
      - 1952 (Box 28)
      - 1953 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence written by Elizabeth Sheffield Thomas
    - To Kendrick Sheffield Few [grandson]
      - 1926 (Box 27)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few [daughter]
      - 1911 (Box 6)
      - 1913-1914, 1917-1918 (Box 6)
      - 1920-1924 (Box 6)
      - 1925 (Box 6)
      - 1926 July-Aug. (Box 7)
      - 1926 (Box 27)
      - 1926 Sept. (Box 7)
      - 1927, undated (Box 7)
      - Last letter from her mother before she died, 1927 (Box 27)
    - To Lyne Starling Thomas [husband]
      - 1913 (Box 7)
      - 1916 (Box 7)
      - 1917 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence written by Lyne Starling Thomas
    - To Elizabeth Sheffield Thomas [wife]
      - 1892, 1905-1906, 1910-1911 (Box 7)
      - 1912-1913 (Box 7)
      - 1914, 1916 (Box 7)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few [daughter]
      - 1912-1914, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To William Preston Few [son-in-law]
      - 1918 (Box 7)
    - To Catherine Sheffield Thomas [daughter]
      - 1911 (Box 7)
    - To Various Individuals
      - 1908 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence written by William Archer Thomas
    - To Elizabeth Sheffield Thomas [mother]
      - 1896, 1900-1905 (Box 7)
      - 1909, 1912-1914, 1916, 1919, 1922, 1924, undated (Box 7)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few [sister]
      - 1935-1936, 1943-1945 (Box 7)
      - Mrs. Archer Thomas, Archer Thomas, 1940-1963, undated (Box 27)
  - Correspondence written by Catherine Sheffield Thomas
    - To Elizabeth Sheffield Thomas [mother]
      - 1909, 1911-1913 (Box 7)
      - 1914-1915, 1917-1918, undated (Box 7)
    - To Lyne Starling Thomas [father]
      - 1911, 1913, 1917 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence written by various Thomas family relatives
    - Mary A. Thomas to Mary Reamey Thomas Few [granddaughter], 1895, 1899, 1906, 1908 (Box 8)
    - Christopher Yancey Thomas to Mary Reamey Thomas Few [cousin], 1951-1958, 1962, 1965-1969 (Box 8)
    - Thomas Family to Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1905, 1908, 1929, 1933, 1940, 1952, 1955, 1970, undated (Box 8)
    - Thomas Family to One Another, 1901, 1951, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Ross-Duggan Family to Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1925, 1930, 1936-1937, 1939-1940, 1943, 1956, 1960, 1965, 1970, undated (Box 8)
    - Catherine Ross-Duggan to Mary Reamey Thomas Few and Randolph Few, 1963-1958 (Box 27)
    - Various Relatives to Mary Reamey Thomas Few: 1911, 1927, 1935, 1945, 1956 (Box 8)
    - Various Relatives to Elizabeth Sheffield Thomas, 1875, 1879, 1880, 1891, 1892, 1896 (Box 8)
    - Various Relatives to Elizabeth Sheffield Thomas, 1901, 1905, 1909-1918, 1921, 1927, undated (Box 8)
    - Various Relatives to Lyne Starling Thomas, 1875, 1891, 1892, 1894, 1901, 1906, 1908, 1915 (Box 8)
    - Various Relatives to Lyne Starling Thomas, 1910-1918, undated (Box 8)
  - Correspondence written by William Preston Few
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few [wife]
      - 1908 (Box 9)
      - 1908-1911, 1921, undated (Box 27)
      - 1909 Jan.-March (Box 9)
      - 1909 April-June (Box 9)
      - 1909 July-Dec. (Box 9)
      - 1910 (Box 9)
      - 1911 (Box 9)
      - 1912 (Box 9)
      - 1913 (Box 9)
      - 1914 (Box 9)
      - 1915 (Box 9)
      - 1916 (Box 10)
      - 1918 (Box 10)
      - 1919 (Box 10)
      - 1920-1923 (Box 10)
      - 1924, 1926-1927, 1929 (Box 10)
      - 1931, 1934, 1938, 1940 (Box 10)
      - Illegible postmark year (Box 10)
      - Undated (Box 10)
    - To Other Relatives [Thomas and Few families]
      - To Lyne Starling Thomas [father-in-law], 1915, 1917-1918 (Box 10)
      - To Elizabeth Sheffield Thomas [mother-in-law], 1913, 1915 (Box 10)
      - To Elizabeth Sheffield Thomas [mother-in-law], 1918, 1919, 1926 (Box 10)
      - To Ellie Few [sister], 1928-1933 (Box 10)
      - To Ellie Few [sister], 1937-1940 (Box 10)
      - To Benjamin Few [nephew], 1930-1937 (Box 11)
      - To Benjamin Few [nephew], 1937-1940 (Box 11)
      - To/about William Few [son], 1928-1940 (Box 11)
      - To/about Lyne Starling Few [son], 1930-1940 (Box 11)
      - To/about Kendrick Sheffield Few [son], 1930-1940 (Box 11)
      - To Randolph Reamey Few [son], 1930, 1937-1938 (Box 11)
      - To Yancy Preston Few [son], 1930, 1938 (Box 11)
      - About Joseph and Marion Few [nephews?], 1929-1930 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence written by various Few family members
    - Benjamin Few to William Preston Few [son], 1893, 1894, 1896, 1903, 1904, 1913, 1914 (Box 11)
    - Ellie Few to William Preston Few [brother], 1898, 1911-1914, 1916 (Box 11)
    - Ellie Few to William Preston Few [brother], circa 1928-1933 (Box 11)
    - Ellie Few to William Preston Few [brother], 1936-1939 (Box 11)
    - Benjamin Few to William Preston Few [uncle], 1930-1937 (Box 11)
    - Benjamin Few to William Preston Few [uncle], 1937-1940 (Box 11)
    - Benjamin Few to Ellie Few [mother?], 1928 Oct. 3 (Box 11)
    - Few Family to William Preston Few, 1897, 1920, circa 1923-1924 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence written by Kendrick Sheffield Few, 1922-1954; 8
    - 1922, 1924, 1931 (Box 27)
      Includes letters to/about Kendrick Few written by other correspondents.
    - To William Preston Few: Asheville School, 1932-1935 (Box 27)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1940 (Box 27)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few: Letters - Harvard, Cambridge, Mass., 1941 (Box 27)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few: Letters from Harvard, Fort Bragg, Fort Washington MD, 1942 (Box 27)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few: Letters - Fort Washington, MD - Ft. Bragg, NC, 1943 (Box 28)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few: Birmingham, AL - Fort Bragg - Army Ground Forces, 1944 (Box 28)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few: Army Ground Forces - Birmingham, AL, 1945 (Box 28)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few: Birmingham, AL - Fort Bragg - Army Ground Forces, 1946 (Box 28)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1947-1950 (Box 28)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1951-1952 (Box 28)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1953 (Box 28)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1954 (Box 28)
  - General Correspondence
    The majority of the correspondence in this subseries is addressed to Mary Reamey Thomas Few. Other recipients of correspondence in this subseries include William Preston Few, Kendrick Sheffield Few, and Yancy Preston Few.
    - 1861, 1864, 1905-1906, 1908 (Box 12)
    - To William Preston Few - W.G. Brown letters, 1896-1913 (Box 28)
    - To William Preston Few, 1896-1940 (Box 28)
    - 1897, 1926-1928, 1965-1970 (Box 28)
    - To William Preston Few - G.L. Kittredge, 1899, 1913, 1934 (Box 28)
    - To William Preston Few and Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1901-1940 (Box 28)
    - 1906-1914 (Box 28)
    - 1909-1911, 1913 (Box 12)
    - To William Preston Few and Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1909, 1918, 1932-1940, undated (Box 28)
    - 1913-1992 (Box 28)
    - 1914-1919 (Box 12)
    - 1920, 1923-1925 (Box 12)
    - 1926-1927 (Box 12)
    - 1928-1929 (Box 12)
    - 1930-1931 (Box 12)
    - 1932-1933 (Box 12)
    - Preston's letters, 1933-1937, undated (Box 28)
    - To William Preston Few and Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1933-1940, undated (Box 28)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 12)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 12)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1937-1939 (Box 28)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1937-1963 (Box 28)
    - 1938 (Box 13)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few and Kendrick Sheffield Few, 1938-1969, undated (Box 28)
    - 1939 (Box 13)
    - Letters of Sorrow: Y. Preston Few [son of Pres. William Preston Few], 1939 (Box 28)
    - Duke Foundation letter from Doris Duke to William Preston Few, 1939 (Box 28)
    - Letters from Eddie Cameron, 1942-1968, undated (Box 28)
    - 1940 (Box 13)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 13)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 13)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1944-1946 (Box 28)
    - SS William Preston Few - Ship in WPF Honor: Photos, Articles, 1944, 1946, 1962 (Box 28)
    - 1945-1949 (Box 13)
    - Martinsville, VA, 1949-1959 (Box 28)
    - 1951-1954 (Box 13)
    - Letters from Kit, 1952-1972 (Box 28)
    - To Kendrick Sheffield Few and Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1952 (Box 28)
    - "Dusted", 1953 (Box 28)
    - 1955 (Box 14)
    - 1955 (Box 28)
    - Dr. Wilbur Cornell Davison, 1955-1970 (Box 28)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 28)
    - 1956 (Box 14)
    - To MRF from Warren Watkins, Sam Ervin, B. Everett Jordan, etc., 1956-1970 (Box 29)
    - 1957 (Box 14)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1958 (Box 29)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 14)
    - Dr. Lenox D. Baker, MD, 1958-1971 (Box 29)
    - WRAL - Jesse Helms, 1959-1971 (Box 29)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 14)
    - 1962 (Box 14)
    - 1963 (Box 14)
    - To Mary Reamey Thomas Few, 1963-1969 (Box 29)
    - 1964 (Box 14)
    - 1965 (Box 14)
    - 1966 (Box 14)
    - 1967 (Box 14)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 15)
    - 1970 (Box 29)
    - 1970-1971, 1986 (Box 15)
    - To Kendrick Sheffield Few: Bob Durden's Launching of D.U. 1987, 1990-1994 (Box 29)
    - Undated (Box 15)
  - Correspondence written by Clarence Poe to Mary Reamey Thomas Few
    - 1908, 1910-1911, 1936, 1944, 1948, 1951-1958 (Box 15)
    - 1958-1964 (Box 27)
      Includes some letters written by other correspondents.
    - 1960-1968, undated (Box 15)
  - Letters about Death of William Preston Few, 1940-1941, 1964; 1
    - Telegrams, 1940; 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Floral Cards, 1940 (Box 27)
    - 1940, 1964, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - 1940-1941, 3 folders (Box 27)
      Third folder includes a letter signed by Julian Abele.
  - Acknowledgements, Thank You Notes, Calling Cards
    - 1904, 1954, 1961, 1970, undated (Box 15)
  - Invitations
    - 1897-1938 (Box 15)
    - 1940-1967 (Box 15)
    - Undated (Box 15)
  - Postcards
    - 1906-1937 (Box 15)
    - 1908-1939, undated (Box 27)
    - Addressed to Mrs. Lyne Sterling Thomas - Mary Reamey Thomas Few's mother (likely part of Ken's postcard collection), 1909-1925, undated (Box 27)
    - Ken's Collection - L.S. Lyne S. Thomas, 1913-1918, undated (Box 27)
    - Dr. W.P. Few, 1915-1937, undated (Box 27)
    - Ken's Collection Misc., 1917-1926, undated (Box 27)
    - Mrs. W.P. Few, 1917-1940, undated (Box 27)
    - To Lyne and Bill, 1920-1921, undated (Box 27)
    - Postcard Book, 1920-1942; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Dr. and Mrs. or Mrs. W.P. Few, 1927-1945, undated (Box 27)
    - Cards to Preston - Misc., 1931, 1937-1938 (Box 27)
    - Unsent Postcards, 1934, 1938, undated (Box 27)
    - 1938-1970, undated (Box 15)
    - Early Hawaii W.F., undated (Box 27)
  - Greeting Cards
    - 1926-1967 (Box 16)
    - With Photographs, 1938, 1942, 1967 (Box 16)
    - Undated (Box 16)
- Genealogy, circa 1898-1980
  Mrs. Few was an avid genealogist with a strong interest in her family history. This series includes research notes she accumulated as well as applications to several historical and genealogical societies. There is also a folder related to the Kendrick family, who were related to Dr. Few.
  - Genealogy, 1898-1920, 1964-1980 (Box 29)
  - Genealogical information, accumulated over a number of years (6 folders) (Box 16)
  - Mary Reamey Thomas Few's application to the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1905; Kendrick Few's application to the Sons of the American Revolution, 1964 (Box 17)
  - Mary Reamey Thomas Few's application to the Huguenot Society, 1940 (Box 17)
  - Mary Reamey Thomas Few's application to the North Carolina Society of Colonial Dames of America, 1923 (Box 17)
  - Kendrick Family Information, accumulated over a number of years (Box 17)
  - Colonial Dames, 1969 (Box 29)
- Miscellaneous, circa 1879-1970
  This series includes material related to Mrs. Few's membership in several historical and genealogical societies, such as newsletters. It also includes printed material, clippings, poems/writings, legal and financial papers, photographs, and the business papers of Lyne Starling Thomas. Thomas was the father of Mary Few and was a lawyer in Martinsville, Va.
  - Huguenot Society, 1941-1970 (Box 17)
  - Magna Charta Dames, 1953-1955, 1968 (Box 17)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, 1915, 1956-1958 (Box 17)
  - Colonial Dames, 1958, undated; Soverign Colonial Society Americans of Royal Descent, 1969 (Box 17)
  - Lyne Starling Thomas: Business Papers, 1904-1905 (Box 17)
  - Lyne Starling Thomas: Business Papers, 1905-1906, 1914-1916 (Box 17)
  - Lyne Starling Thomas: Business Papers, 1897, 1900-1902 (Box 17)
  - Lyne Starling Thomas: Business Papers, 1902, 1911, 1916, 1918, 1920, 1922 (Box 17)
  - Lyne Starling Thomas: Business Papers, 1913-1920 (Box 17)
  - Lyne Starling Thomas: Business Papers, 1915, 1917-1920 (Box 17)
  - Lyne Starling Thomas: Business Papers, 1917 (Box 17)
  - Lyne Starling Thomas: Business Papers, 1918-1920 (Box 17)
  - Lyne Starling Thomas: Business Papers, 1917, 1919, undated (Box 17)
  - Legal and Financial Papers, circa 1879-1967 (Box 18)
  - Trinity College/Duke University-related Items, circa 1906-1970, undated (Box 18)
  - Poems/Writings, undated (Box 18)
  - Photographs, 1939, 1955, 1961, undated (Box 18)
  - Printed Material, circa 1906-1969, undated (Box 18)
  - Printed Material, 1934, 1939, 1967 (Box 18)
  - Clippings, 1885, 1920s (Box 18)
  - Clippings, 1930s (Box 19)
  - Clippings, 1940s-1970s (Box 19)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 19)
  - The Martinsville Herald, 1885 Nov. 13 (Box 19)
  - The Dukes (a play), 1963-1965 (Box 19)